Sunomata is a strategically
important point
where the Nagara River intersects
with several others.
A fortification built here would
all but guarantee control of Mino.
However...
Inabayama Castle is very close by,
and any attempt to build something here would quickly be met with overwhelming force.
A
Sunomata is a graveyard.
Even a graveyard can
come to birth new life.
Even a graveyard can come to birth new life.
Oda Nobuna no Yabou
The moment you swing the sword you pledged upon
You get hurt again
Biting down on my lip
I try to figure out what the right thing is
I will protect you, but before that
There's something I must do
I'm not trying to stand out
I just don't want to be a liar
I live on the battlefield with my life on the line
Whenever I look back, you're there to reassure me
The days of sorrow end, and the sun of ambition rises
Let's defeat fate and go as far as we want
Linking the world
Episode Six
Sunomata Castle
So, the invasion of Mino will ride on what happens at Sunomata.
Pretty clever.
We need to make this work.
Yoshitatsu won't just sit
back and let it happen.
Then you convince him, Viper.
Impossible.
It's eat or be eaten.
Like father, like son.
Then we'll just have to build
a fort however we can.
You'll build nothing more
than a pile of bodies.
Making a fort in Sunomata is impossible.
Hanbei, what do you think?
I-I think that whoever controls
Sunomata controls Mino.
Only by doing the impossible c-can
you prove yourself worthy to rule.
So, the genius strategist
is pretty smart.
You're thinking just what I am.
Drop the monkey and serve me.
That's an order.
B-But...
Hey, Nobuna...
I-I'm sorry!
I've sworn to serve Mr. Yoshiharu!
Hanbei...
I see!
Monkey will help me,
and you help him.
Do everything you can
to help me conquer.
Th-Thank you!
So,
our plans for building the fort...
It's finally time for this event?
I've seen this event dozens of times
in Legends of the Civil Wars!
The overnight construction of
the fort at Sunomata!
...will be entrusted to Shibata Katsuie.
Why?!
Do you have a problem with that?
I sure do!
Obviously it should be me!
I don't want anybody to think I'm
giving you special treatment.
After Okehazama and convincing Hanbei to defect,
some people might be unhappy
that you're getting all the glory.
There you have it.
I'm counting on you, Katsuie.
Leave it to me.
Why are you all so scared?!
Do you think you can
beat Nobuna like that?!
Hanbei's defection has
become well known.
The soldiers' morale is low.
A genius strategist and
Oda's powerful armies...
In an even match, she'll
burn Mino to the ground.
What are you trying to say?
It might be worth working with
her like Count Dousan did.
Never let me hear you say that again!
B-But...
Dousan chose Nobuna, not me!
I'll never forget that humiliation.
Reporting!
Oda is attempting to construct
a fortification in Sunomata!
In Sunomata?!
The fool is at our mercy.
Take your men and destroy her.
Yes, sir!
When we've slain Nobuna,
I shall make you the new Mino Three.
Stay strong!
Put out the fire!
Constructing a fort
like this is impossible.
We need to do it no matter what!
General Katsuie, we must retreat!
Damn it all!
So not only Shibata, but Niwa and
Sakuma have failed as well.
Sunomata must be a vision of hell itself.
In all likelihood, Monkey will try next.
Monkey?
The man who took Hanbei from you?
He'll possibly...
No. He'll definitely do
something unexpected.
You seem impressed by him.
But... in the end,
the one to take Mino and Nobuna, will be none other than me.
You can't just keep sending
people out there to get killed!
The standard methods won't work!
Why won't you let me do it?
Because you always do something crazy.
Are you... worried about me?
It's natural for a lord to be
worried about her retainers!
I-I'm not worried about
you specifically.
Please let me do it!
You have a plan, don't you?
Yeah.
Build it in just one night!
In one night?
If it goes up in a single night,
they won't be able to stop it.
It's strange. When you say it,
it actually sounds possible.
What's this?
If you're leading an operation of this size, you're a real general.
You'll need a symbol on your
flag for your monkey armies.
A gourd?
Toyotomi Hideyoshi conquered Japan
under the sign of the gourd.
So, it is the same...
No. I won't let that happen!
I'll make sure the one who
conquers Japan is Nobuna!
I'll take it gladly.
This is an order.
Come back alive.
Yes, ma'am!
Move out!
So, we have from dusk till dawn.
Yeah. We will make this work.
Nobuna's on the march?
Yes. She's taken almost her
entire army toward Kisogawa.
So, she's given up on Sunomata?
I'll give you 2,000 men.
Bring me Nobuna's head.
Without you, sir?
Stay calm.
It's all part of the plan.
Yoshitatsu's forces have
left Inabayama Castle.
Looks like we drew them out.
This way, we'll keep them well away from Sunomata.
But still... using you as a decoy...
It's all part of the plan.
Once we've cut down enough trees,
we'll start assembling them
into parts for the fort.
This is beyond belief.
It's a construction technique
from the future.
You make the parts for a
building somewhere else,
carry them to the area, and
build the structure quickly.
You're way too proud of that.
A splendid strategy.
The question is whether
Miss Nobuna can make it back
before our defensive forces are spent.
We don't need to worry about Nobuna.
Monkey...
Lord Nobuna,
something's strange about the
movement of Yoshitatsu's forces.
What do you mean?
They've headed for a narrow
space between two mountains.
I believe they're trying to lure us in.
An abandoned gold mine?
They must be planning
to use it as a stronghold.
It's fine that we're drawing
them away from Sunomata,
but if we take too long getting
back, Monkey and his men...
Why don't we just destroy them here?
Our goal here is the construction
of a fort at Sunomata.
In that case, shall we send the army back?
You lead them away from me.
I'll build the fort while you do!
We'll continue with the decoy plan.
We're ready to welcome them, yes?
Indeed.
None of them will survive.
But what of Inaba and the others?
They will be sacrificed to kill
Nobuna and ensure Mino's safety.
I'm sure they won't mind.
All rafts, head for Sunomata!
Yoshitatsu's forces have set up camp
on the other side of this town.
Let's be careful.
If we're surrounded here, it's over.
Enemy attack!
Follow the plan!
Right!
You will be decoys, drawing Nobuna in.
I will attack from behind
with our main force.
A splendid plan, one worthy
of the Viper's son!
If only he was more of a man!
If we can defeat Oda here,
perhaps that means he really is!
Why do I have to help?
Shut up and work.
Make sure it doesn't fall apart.
No one at Inabayama Castle has noticed us yet.
I see.
Let it stay that way... please!
It's dangerous to go too deep.
But they're persistent.
Don't forget.
We have to be at Sunomata by dawn.
They're taking too long!
When is Lord Yoshitatsu
going to get here?!
All we're doing is losing men!
Princess!
Something's wrong.
We can't find Yoshitatsu in their camp!
What was that?
Come to think of it, it's only Inaba and
Ujiie's men who are fighting here.
What's going on?
Oh, no! It's a trap!
Wh-What?
What's going on?
The whole area's been laced with oil.
Yoshitatsu tricked us.
Lord Yoshitatsu is planning on
killing us here with Nobuna!
We've been tricked!
Unbelievable!
The flames have surrounded us.
There's nowhere to run.
At this rate, Monkey will...
Nobuna's trapped by the fire!
At last...
At last, I have won!
I'll have Owari, Mikawa,
and Oumi for my own!
M-My lord!
Disaster!
What's all this ruckus?
A-A fort...
A fort in Sunomata!
What?!
R-Ridiculous...
It can't be...
A fort built overnight?
I can't believe it!
March!
Destroy that fort!
They're here!
They're coming!
Hanbei...
Not yet.
Sun Tzu's Art of War tells us
we should strike when most of their forces have crossed the river.
Riflemen, open fire!
Bowmen, target the troops
still in the river!
Curse you, Hanbei.
Nobuna's forces will arrive soon!
Hold out until they do!
Everyone, don't give up!
The enemy!
Damn it!
Princess!
Nobody move.
You must be Oda Nobuna.
We are but fools abandoned by our lord.
Now all that is left is
to choose a place to die.
If we can take you with us,
we shall keep our pride as warriors.
That's stupid.
Of course it's better that you don't die.
If you haven't tried as
hard as you can to live,
how can you seek a place to die?
Live, live, keep living 'til the end!
You can think about where to
die when you're in your coffin!
Got it?!
You're telling us to survive?
In this situation?
Of course.
Everyone, get all the
gunpowder you can find.
If this was a gold mine, there
should still be some about.
We're out of ammunition!
The east side can't hold.
At this rate, we'll be wiped out.
I'll use my double to open
us a path to escape.
We'll protect Sunomata.
I promised Nobuna we would.
I won't let us get wiped out.
I love the way you don't
want to abandon anything.
But...
You're too greedy, Yoshiharu.
I... I won't give up.
Nobuna will come!
Sagara!
Go-Goemon!
I'm coming, Monkey!
She blew away the fire with gunpowder.
Fighting fire with fire?
Who would think of something so insane?
But it's exciting, isn't it?
Like the first time we met Count Dousan.
Yes. I think I understand why Andou and Hanbei joined her.
Let us make it, please!
Wake up, Goemon!
Goemon!
Is this really happening?
Was I too childish?!
Tell me...
Nobuna!
Hurry! Go faster!
No.
This isn't happening.
I couldn't have been too late.
Monkey...
Monkey!
You're late, Nobuna!
All forces,
charge!
Nobuna should be dead!
But it's definitely her!
And Inaba and Ujiie have defected!
Our forces are routed!
Ludicrous.
This is ludicrous!
Now both armies are at my mercy.
I won't let you pass.
Niwa?
The princess sent me.
This battle is Sagara Yoshiharu's.
If any coward tries to interfere...
even if it's Asai Nagamasa,
she's ordered me to kill them.
We managed to win...
but...
G-Goemon?
Every ninja wears chain mail.
I got knocked out, but...
Y-You idiot!
It's good for greedy Yoshiharu
to experience losing something for onc—
Let me go!
You can't just g-g-grab me!
If you do that... I'll just... It's too...
Saitou Yoshitatsu was captured,
and at last, Mino became the
territory of the Oda clan.
And Nobuna renamed
Inabayama Castle as Gifu Castle.
Kill me already.
As long as I'm alive, I'll fight you.
That's right. Kill him.
Stop being stubborn and enjoy
your retirement together.
Impossible.
Fine.
Inuchiyo, cut Yoshitatsu's ropes.
Wh-What?
You're taking pity on me?
You mustn't!
That naïveté will cost
you your life someday.
Be quiet!
It's my decision.
You foolish girl!
My father was correct just now.
You really are a fool.
You just spared his life.
How can he say that?
It's fine.
Really, both of them are so stubborn.
Next, the matter of rewards...
Just a second.
Before we get to that...
You're looking pretty gloomy.
Because of me, she's left
herself an enemy.
It bothers me.
Nobuna didn't want you to carry
the sin of killing your son.
She's naïve! Far too naïve!
I'm an old fool who should already be dead.
"Dousan the Viper."
A few more evil deeds at this
point mean nothing to me.
I should've died at Nagara River.
I'm not worthy to be her father.
You blind old man!
Look out there.
And say the new name of this castle.
Wh-What?
Have a long life.
You're the only father she has left.
What's out there?
tada jidai no mannaka tatasarete tomadou toki ni
When I, lost in time, was standing there confused
This is...
From now on, this is Gifu Castle.
And the town of Gifu.
te wo hiite kureta hito e dekiru koto sagashita
You pulled me through, so I wanted to do something in return
Gifu Castle...
"Gifu," meaning stepfather...
kizutsuki nagara warau sugata
You were smiling even though you were being hurt
kokoro no ura namida ga mieta
I saw you shedding tears deep inside
sukui motomeru koe kikitoreru no wa
I could only understand your call for help
yurusareta mono dake
When you opened up to me
kazoe kirenu arashi wo koete
I will overcome the countless storms
anata no yami saku hikari ni naru
And become the light that cuts through your darkness
mou mayowanai tomo ni ikitai
I won't hesitate anymore; let's go together
chikau yume ga donna mubou de atte mo
No matter how unrealistic our ambitions are
oboeteite shinjirareru basho wa
Remember there's a place you can believe in
koko ni aru to
Right here
Episode Seven
Nobuna Advances
on Kyoto
Episode Seven
Nobuna Advances
on Kyoto
Episode Seven
Nobuna Advances
on Kyoto
Episode Seven
Nobuna Advances
on Kyoto